kikkomanusa.com 2015-06-12

# Recipes, Cooking Products and More for Home Cooks - Kikkoman : Privacy

Thank you for visiting our website, www.kikkomanusa.com (“Site”). Kikkoman Sales USA, Inc. (“Kikkoman”, “we” or “us”), the operator of this Site, is committed to protecting and safeguarding your privacy. This document will outline how we gather and utilize various sources of information obtained during your visit to the Site. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected at this Site. If you have any questions, please do not hesitate to let us know. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY, YOU MAY NOT ACCESS OR OTHERWISE USE THE SITE. 

## Personal and Non-Personal Information:

When using the Site, in order to utilize some of the services, you may be asked to provide, or you may choose to upload, certain personally identifiable information about yourself ("Personal Information"). Personal Information can include your name, birth date, gender, email address, physical address, telephone number or other information you may provide. Similarly, when you post a photograph, enter or respond to a contest, survey, sweepstakes or other promotional feature, we may ask you for your name, physical address, email address or other Personal Information.

In addition, we may also collect non-personally identifiable information, such as IP host address, pages viewed, browser type, duration and frequency of visits, and other data, and may aggregate any information collected in a manner which does not identify any individual ("Aggregate Information"). We obtain Aggregate Information from our Site logs which we analyze to improve the quality and value of the materials available on our Site. Our Site logs are not personally identifiable, and we make no attempt to link them with the individuals who actually browse the Site. This means that, in general, you can visit our Site without telling us who you are or revealing Personal Information about yourself, in which case you may, however, be unable to participate in certain promotions or receive product information.

Information obtained in connection with the Site may be intermingled with and used by us in conjunction with information obtained through sources other than the Site, including both offline and online sources.

## Information Collected On The Site And How We Use It:

We may use the Personal Information we collect to contact you about our products and services or those of our partners or other third parties. We may also use the Personal Information you have voluntarily submitted to respond, including via email, to your inquiries and your comments or requests for information, or to contact you, if needed, in the course of processing or shipping products or services offered over our Site. We do not sell your Personal Information to third parties or mass marketers. For example, we will not sell another company your name or email address. Unless you consent to the disclosure of your Personal Information, only we and our affiliates, our technical consultants, third party auditors and other third parties who make our Site available, enhance its functionality, or provide associated services and/or who deal with you in delivering content, samples, products, gifts and prizes, have access to this information, and we require them to agree that they are covered by this policy.

Please note that Kikkoman reserves the right to and may disclose Personal Information about you in response to (a) requests from local, state or federal law enforcement officials;

(b) any judicial, administrative or similar proceeding or order, such as subpoena; (c) if required by law; or (d) to investigate suspected fraud, harassment, physical threats, or other violations of any law, rule or regulation, the Site rules or policies, or the rights of third parties or to investigate any suspected conduct which we deem improper. Please also note that we do reserve the right to transfer your personally identifiable information and other information to our successors in business and purchasers of Site assets.

## Cookies:

"Cookies" are pieces of information that may be placed on your computer by a web site for the purpose of facilitating and enhancing your communication and interaction with that web site. Cookies help us in many ways to make your visit to our Site more enjoyable and meaningful to you. For example, we may use cookies (or clear gifs or similar devices) to customize your visit to the Site and for other purposes to make your visit more convenient or to enable us to enhance our Site. You may stop or restrict the placement of cookies on your computer or flush them from your browser by adjusting your web browser preferences. However, turning cookies off may cause certain Site features not to be available to visitors and may interfere with the Site’s functionality. Kikkoman may also use "web beacons" to access the information contained in its cookies within the network of the Kikkoman web sites, newsletter emails, and interactive banner ads.

## Clickstream:

As you use the Internet, a trail of electronic information is left at each web site you visit. This information, which is sometimes referred to as "clickstream data," can be collected and stored by a web site's server. Clickstream data can tell us the type of computer and browsing software you use and the address of the web site from which you linked to the Site. We may collect and use clickstream data as a form of Aggregate Information to anonymously determine how much time visitors spend on each page of our Site, how visitors navigate throughout the Site and how we may tailor our web pages to better meet the needs of visitors. This information will be used to improve our Site and our services. Any collection or use of clickstream data will be anonymous and aggregate, and will not intentionally contain any Personal Information.

## Protection for Children:

We have no intention of collecting Personal Information from children under the age of 13. When we become aware that personal information from a child under 13 has been collected without such child’s parent or guardian’s consent, we will use all reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database.

## Security:

Kikkoman will not be liable for disclosures of your Personal Information due to errors in transmission or unauthorized acts of third parties. We have undertaken all commercially reasonable efforts to prevent unauthorized Internet access to visitor data retained in our servers, however, due to the inherent open nature of the Internet, Kikkoman cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or any information provided online, and you do so at your own risk. Users must accept all risks associated with any data transmission, including the risk that their Personal Information may be intercepted in transit.

## Links To Other Sites:

Our Site may contain links to other web sites. Other web sites may also reference or link to our Site. These "other" domains (web sites) are not controlled by Kikkoman and, thus, Kikkoman has no control over the privacy practices or the content of such websites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our Site to read the privacy policies of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. We do not endorse, screen or approve, and are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other web sites. Visiting these other web sites is at your own risk.

## Bulletin Boards and Chat Areas:

You should be aware that Personal Information which you voluntarily include and transmit online may be viewed and used by others. Users of the Site are solely responsible for the content of messages they post online including on public forums. These forums include but are not limited to on and offsite chat rooms, bulletin boards, blogs or other publicly accessible forums which may be viewed and used by anyone with access to such forums. Users should be aware that when they voluntarily disclose Personal Information within a public forum that user information may be collected and used by others. The Site is unable to control such uses of your Personal Information, and by using such services you assume the risk that the Personal Information provided by you may be viewed and used by third parties.

## Policy Modifications/Opt-Out:

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this Privacy Policy at any time. However, if at any time in the future we plan to use Personal Information in a way that differs from this Privacy Policy, we will post such changes here. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of any changes to this policy means you accept such changes. Please check this page periodically for changes to this Privacy Policy.

We give you the option to remove your Personal Information from any lists that we maintain of users. All unsubscribe or opt-out requests should be sent to us at consumer@kikkoman.com and we will process your request within a reasonable time after receipt. We are not responsible for removing your Personal Information from the lists of any third party who has previously been provided your information in accordance with this policy.

## Site Terms and Conditions:

Use of this Site is governed by, and subject to, the Terms and Conditions contained at http://www.kikkomanusa.com/privacy/terms.php Your use, or access, of the Site constitutes your agreement to be bound by these Terms and Conditions.

## Comments and Questions:

If you have any questions, comments or concerns about our Privacy Policy, you may contact us at the following address:

Kikkoman Sales USA, Inc.  
Consumer Services  
50 California St., Ste#3600  
San Francisco, California 94111  
United States of America

Our Site is maintained in the United States of America. By using the Site, you authorize the export of Personal Information to the USA and its storage and use as specified in this policy.

Effective Date: This privacy policy is effective and was last updated on January 26, 2009.
